Hi, this is Sean Hobson and what we're talking about right now is using the proper mechanics to become not only a good shooter, but a good shooter from the free throw line.
So the last step that we have is to finish out your free throw.
If Kyle steps up to the line right here and gets himself ready.
What we're going to talk about is you have a good base, you have a good foundation.
You're going to make the shot; you're going to follow through at the end of the shot.
That's the first thing in finishing.
But the most important thing is by using your legs, a lot of time you see players come up and shoot their free throw and they stay flat footed and then end up hitting the ball on the front of the rim.
What we always want to do is you always want to finish your free throw up on your toes because what that does is when you get up on your toes, that's using the bottom of your leg muscles and its giving you just that extra edge to get that ball up and over the rim.
The other thing you want to make sure and do is always follow through and end up out in front of you.
You never want to end up with the ball up here.
What we see a lot of players do is they'll follow through, but then they'll pull their hand back and again, that's going to pull that basketball back a little bit and not let it go ahead and follow through the proper way.
The last thing is we don't want to fall take our shot and fall back off the free throw line.
If you shoot and you take a step back, it?s called negative energy.
You're taking energy away from that basketball and not allowing it to go on down.
So, remember when making a good free throw shot, its not just the shot, its also how you finish after the free throw that's going to make you a good free throw shooter.